Trey Arnold

Email: <u>arnold.trey80@gmail.com</u> | Phone: 281-774-8332 | Spring, TX 77379 GitHub: <u>https://github.com/treyarnold</u> | LinkedIn: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/trey-arnold/</u>

Portfolio: https://heytrey.dev/

Full Stack Web Developer with an eye for inter-functionality and breaking down problems. Enjoys utilizing experience with client facing roles to clearly convey designs and maintain usability as a focus while keeping client needs first. Passionate about creating function with form and approaching challenges from new directions. Holds communication in high regard; works well when collaborating with others or independently.

Technical Skills: JavaScript, ¡Query, Node, MongoDB, Git, Github, API, HTML5, CSS3

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Project 1 | Full Stack Developer

- RESTful app where you can add, comment and review campgrounds. Authentication is used for all paths after the initial show page
- Using the new bootstrap card-deck, I came up with a solution to wrap all the campsites inside the deck and dynamically change the number of cards per row based on view size and number of cards in the DB
- Tools/languages used: Node, MongoDB, JavaScript, Bootstrap4, HTML5, CSS3
- https://github.com/treyarnold/yelp_camp | https://campbnb.herokuapp.com/

Project 2 | Front-end Developer

- Word guessing game using a Harry Potter theme. Your wins and losses are tracked
- I created a virtual keyboard to make the game more user friendly. Letters will disappear as they are used.
- Tools/languages used: JavaScript, Bootstrap4, HTML5, CSS3
- https://github.com/treyarnold/potterWords | https://treyarnold.github.io/potterWords/

Project 3 | Front-end Developer

- Trivia game using a Game of Thrones theme. Your wins and losses are tracked.
 Questions are timed.
- 10 random questions are assigned each time you play. Entire bank of options is currently at 20 questions
- Tools/languages used: JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap4, HTML5, CSS3
- https://github.com/treyarnold/TriviaGame | https://treyarnold.github.io/TriviaGame/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Trelevate

Energy Consultant, November 2018 - Present

- Built and maintained lead pipeline in commercial energy sales
- Tripled new sales quotas in an entirely new industry
- All Texas offices closing due to client financial difficulties. Letter from client stating situation available upon request

Power Home Remodeling Group

Remodeling Consultant, February 2016 - October 2018

- Met with pre qualified clients to inspect their home and determine what their needs are in order to showcase our portfolio and to complete a one call close
- Lead weekly meetings in a continuing education format to train and polish sales personnel
- Responsible for training new hires in client relationships, sales, overcoming objections, designing remodeling packages and operations procedures
- Salesman of the Month Nov 2017

Pappas Restaurants

Restaurant Manager, March 2013 - January 2016

- Responsible for all front and back of the house operations including, receiving of goods, inventory controls, food prep, cooking of orders, final plating and presentation while providing for meals of up to 60 people per table
- Responsible for manager and staff development emphasizing teamwork and customer service
- Handled competitive bidding for daily and weekly ordering
- Ensured receiving of goods are up to quality and match orders

Texas Western Hospitality

Sales Manager, August 2010 – March 2013

- Increased revenue in 2012 by 16.1% while our comp set only increased by 10%
- Surpassed budget sales goals for 2012 by over 6.5%
- Knowledge of Marriott pricing strategies and techniques
- Decreased cost of goods sold by over 8% for the entire hotel
- Trained employees on front desk operations

EDUCATION

University of Texas, Austin, TX

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap4, Firebase, Node, Mysql, MongoDB, Express & React js.

University of North Texas, Denton, TX

Hospitality Management

CERTIFICATIONS

Web Developer Bootcamp